In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to pronounce the L consonant sound.
我们将学习如何发L辅音音。
This sound is especially difficult.
这个音特别难。
There are actually two kinds of Ls,
实际上有两种L音，
and they're not made the same way.
它们的发音方式不同。
But if you look up a word in the dictionary,
但如果你查字典，
there's only one international phonetic alphabet symbol for both kinds of L.
国际音标中只有一个符号表示这两种L音。
In this video, you'll learn when to make which kind of L.
在这个视频中，你将学习何时发哪种L音。
First,
首先，
the light L sound.
轻L音。
This is what most people think of when they think of an L.
这就是大多数人想到L时想到的音。
The L is a light L when it comes before the vowel or diphthong in a syllable.
当L在音节中出现在元音或双元音之前时，它是轻L音。
For example, let's.
例如，let's。
Flake.
flake。
Release.
release。
There are two different ways native speakers make this sound.
母语者发这个音有两种不同的方式。
One way is to lift the tongue so the tip is touching the roof of the mouth,
一种方式是抬起舌头，使舌尖接触上颚，
just behind the front teeth.
就在前牙的后面。
This is not the same as the T,
这与T，
D, and N tongue positions,
D和N的舌位不同，
where the tongue lifts so the top is touching the roof of the mouth.
它们是舌头抬起，使顶部接触上颚。
This is the tip.
这是舌尖。
Another way native speakers make this sound looks like the TH,
母语者发这个音的另一种方式看起来像TH，
with the tongue tip touching the bottom of the top front teeth.
舌尖接触上前牙的底部。
The contact with the teeth is more firm than the TH sound,
与TH音相比，牙齿的接触更紧，
pushing up on the top teeth.
向上推上牙。
The tongue is not as loose or relaxed in the L as it is in the TH.
在L音中，舌头不像在TH音中那样松弛或放松。
Let's look at the light L up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察轻L音。
Here's one way to make the L,
这是发L音的一种方式，
with the tongue tip coming through the teeth to press up on the bottom of the top front teeth.
舌尖穿过牙齿，向上推上前牙的底部。
Here's the second way to make the light L,
这是发轻L音的第二种方式，
the tip at the roof of the mouth,
舌尖在上颚，
just behind the teeth.
就在牙齿的后面。
The teeth to make the light L.
牙齿发轻L音。
The word slow.
单词slow。
The light L is made with the tongue tip at the roof of the mouth.
轻L音是舌尖在上颚发出的。
The second kind of L is the dark L.
第二种L音是重L音。
This is the sound that happens when the L comes after the vowel or diphthong in a word or syllable,
当L在单词或音节中出现在元音或双元音之后时，就是这个音，
like real or Google.
例如real或Google。
This sound has two parts,
这个音有两个部分，
but many Americans leave out the second part in most cases.
但许多美国人在大多数情况下省略了第二部分。
You should too.
你也应该这样做。
It makes it easier to pronounce.
这使得发音更容易。
The first and most important part of the dark L is the dark sound.
重L音的第一个也是最重要的部分是重音。
This defines the dark L.
这定义了重L音。
To make this sound,
要发这个音，
you don't lift your tongue tip.
你不抬起舌尖。
Instead, it's down, touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
相反，它向下，接触下前牙的后面。
The back part of the tongue pulls back towards the throat.
舌头的后部向喉咙方向拉回。
You can see there isn't much jaw drop,
你可以看到下巴没有太多下垂，
and the lips are relaxed.
嘴唇是放松的。
You should feel the vibration in the throat and not the face.
你应该在喉咙而不是脸上感到振动。
The back part of the tongue presses down or shifts back.
舌头的后部向下压或向后移动。
This is an important part of the sound.
这是音的重要部分。
Most Americans will stop there when making the dark L.
大多数美国人在发重L音时会停在这里。
Real.
real。
Google.
Google。
Thoughtful.
thoughtful。
Unless they're linking into a word that begins with an L,
除非他们要连接到以L开头的单词，
or a sound with a similar position, like N, T,
或位置相似的音，如N，T，
or D.
或D。
In that case, go ahead and make the second part of the dark L.
在这种情况下，继续发重L音的第二部分。
The second part of the dark L is the light L.
重L音的第二部分是轻L音。
Bring your tongue tip up to the roof of the mouth or through the teeth.
将舌尖抬到上颚或穿过牙齿。
Some native speakers make the full dark L, both parts,
一些母语者总是完整地发重L音，两个部分，
all the time.
一直如此。
What's important is the dark sound.
重要的是重音。
Make it with the back of the tongue.
用舌头的后部发出。
And make sure you never leave that part out.
确保你永远不要省略那部分。
Lll.
Lll。
Again, the dark L has two parts.
再次，重L音有两个部分。
The first and most important part.
第一个也是最重要的部分。
The tongue pulls back,
舌头向后拉，
or presses down in the back.
或在后部向下压。
The second part, which is often left out.
第二部分，通常被省略。
Either option for the light L.
轻L音的任一选项。
Here,
这里，
the option with the tongue tip at the roof of the mouth is pictured.
舌尖在上颚的选项被展示。
Let's look at the dark L up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察重L音。
The word feel.
单词feel。
The tongue tip arches in the front for the E vowel.
舌尖在E元音时在前部拱起。
Watch as the tongue lowers in the back.
观察舌头在后部如何降低。
Now the tongue is lowered,
现在舌头降低了，
pulling back a little bit in the back.
在后部稍微向后拉。
It's hard to see because of the lips,
因为嘴唇的关系，很难看到，
but the tip of the tongue is still forward.
但舌尖仍然在前面。
Notice that the lips are relaxed.
注意嘴唇是放松的。
The word recall.
单词recall。
The dark part is made with the back of the tongue as the jaw closes.
重音是用舌头的后部发出的，当下巴闭合时。
This time, the dark L does end with the second part, the light L.
这次，重L音以第二部分结束，即轻L音。
The tongue tip quickly comes through the teeth.
舌尖迅速穿过牙齿。
Lips are relaxed.
嘴唇是放松的。
The relaxation of the lips is important in the dark L.
嘴唇的放松在重L音中很重要。
Many non-native speakers want to round or flare the lips,
许多非母语者想要圆或张开嘴唇，
which brings the sound forward and changes it.
这会将声音向前带并改变它。
But the dark sound is made back here.
但重音是在这里发出的。
Leave the lips relaxed so the sound can be made in the back of the mouth.
让嘴唇放松，以便声音可以在口腔后部发出。
When you look at the International Phonetic Alphabet transcription for a word in a dictionary,
当你在字典中查看单词的国际音标转录时，
you'll just see one symbol,
你只会看到一个符号，
whether it's a light L or a dark L.
无论是轻L还是重L。
It's up to you to know when to make a dark L when the L comes at the end of a syllable.
当L在音节末尾时，知道何时发重L音取决于你。
Remember, we're talking about sounds and not letters.
记住，我们谈论的是声音而不是字母。
In the example,
在例子中，
Google,
Google，
you see the letter E after the L.
你看到L后面有字母E。
E is a vowel,
E是一个元音，
but when you look at the phonetic transcription of the word,
但当你查看单词的音标转录时，
the last sound is the L.
最后一个音是L。
So the L in Google is a dark L.
所以Google中的L是重L音。
L, L.
L，L。
Google.
Google。
If you integrate a good dark L into your speech,
如果你在讲话中融入一个好的重L音，
it will help you sound more American.
这将帮助你听起来更像美国人。
L, L.
L，L。
Feel.
Feel。
Recall.
Recall。
Example words.
例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Love.
Love。
L.
L。
Love.
Love。
Hello.
Hello。
L.
L。
Hello.
Hello。
Flat.
Flat。
L.
L。
Flat.
Flat。
Feel.
Feel。
L.
L。
Feel.
Feel。
Table.
Table。
L.
L。
Table.
Table。
People.
People。
L.
L。
People.
People。